Register of the Romanov family papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Romanov family papers
1847-2003
2013C18
Hoover Institution Archives
45 manuscript boxes, 20 oversize boxes (50.1 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoirs, other writings, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia relating to the Russian aristocracy and to Russian émigré affairs following the Russian Revolution.
K. R. (Konstantin Romanov), Grand Duke of Russia, 1858-1915.
Romanov family.
Access
Closed. Microfilm use only. Boxes 56 and 59-65 were not filmed.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2013.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Descendants of Grand Duke Konstantin Konstantinovich of Russia.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Romanov family papers include writings, notes, clippings, printed matter, and photographs relating to various members of the Romanov family and other Russian dignitaries and nobility; events in Russia before, during, and after the Russian Revolution; Russian immigration to foreign countries; and the Russian Orthodox Church abroad. The bulk of the collection consists of extensive correspondence between family members and individuals connected closely with the Russian Imperial family relating to personal matters in the lives of the family. The collection also includes Romanov family memorabilia.
The papers consist primarily of materials collected by the descendants of Grand Duke Konstantin Konstantinovich of Russia, a grandson of Emperor Nicholas I of Russia. Materials were collected by the Bagration branch of the Romanov family and were donated to the Hoover Institution Archives by Grand Duke Konstantin Konstantinovich Romanov’s granddaughter-in-law Irina Bezobrazova-Bagration.
Arrangement Statement
Original arrangement of the collection into trunks, bags, and cartons has been retained. However, material within each storage trunk has been described in greater detail and arranged within each one, either by subject or physical form.
Romanov, House of.; Nobility--Russia.; Russia--Emigration and immigration.; Russia--History--Nicholas II, 1894-1917.
- Princess Vera Konstantinovna (Constantinovna) of Russia papers from black trunk no. 1, 1887-2003
  - Biographical file, 1906-2003
    Arrangement Statement
    Arranged alphabetically by physical form.
    - Birth certificate, 1906 (Reel 1)
      Box/Folder 1: 1
    - Employment related documents, 1949-1951
      Box/Folder 1: 2
    - Immigration papers, 1951-1961
      Box/Folder 1: 3
    - List of personal belongings, 1918-1952
      Box/Folder 1: 4
      Includes invitations, medical prescriptions, and bills.
    - Obituaries, 1998-2003
      Box/Folder 1: 5-9
      Includes writings, correspondence, photographs, printed matter, and piece of Princess Vera Konstantinovna's crib blanket.
  - Correspondence, 1901-1989
    Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
    - General, 1901-1989
      Box/Folder 1: 10-12
    - Aleksandr Mikhailovich, Grand Duke of Russia, 1923 (Reel 2)
      Box/Folder 1: 13
    - Alferieff, Eugene E., 1982
      Box/Folder 1: 14
      Includes photographs depicting Prince Dmitrii Konstantinovich (Constantinovich) Romanov.
    - Andrei Vladimirovich, Grand Duke of Russia, 1937-1950
      Box/Folder 1: 15
    - Aprelev, Boris Petrovich, 1935-1938
      Box/Folder 1: 16
    - Born (Borotinski), Helen, 1984
      Box/Folder 1: 17
    - Carobon, Julia N., 1934
      Box/Folder 1: 18
    - Deitrikh, Vladimir, 1934-1948
      Box/Folder 1: 19
    - Ernest, Frederick, 1987
      Box/Folder 1: 20
    - Garshine, M., 1932-1937
      Box/Folder 1: 21
    - Ivanov, G., 1979-1980
      Box/Folder 1: 22
    - Johnston, Charles, 1984
      Box/Folder 1: 23
    - Kepping, Boris von, 1922-1937
      Box/Folder 1: 24
    - Kolomeitsev, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1920-1937
      Box/Folder 1: 25
    - Kulikovskii, Tikhon, 1988
      Box/Folder 1: 26
    - Kurth, Peter L., 1971
      Box/Folder 1: 27
    - Leporskii, Sergei, 1968
      Box/Folder 1: 28
    - Lukomskii, Sergei Vladimirovich, 1941
      Box/Folder 1: 29
    - Manshtein, Aleksandr Sergeevich, circa 1930
      Box/Folder 1: 30
    - Nashchekin, Vladimir Sergeevich, 1987
      Box/Folder 1: 31
    - Nikolai Romanovich, Prince of Russia, 1929-1985
      Box/Folder 1: 32-33
    - Novopashennyi, N., 1937-1941
      Box/Folder 1: 34
    - Ososov, Dmitrii Ivanovich, 1976
      Box/Folder 1: 35
      Includes Romanov family genealogy charts.
    - Ostroumov, Nikolai Antonovich, 1981-1982
      Box/Folder 1: 36
    - Politovskii, S., 1933-1935
      Box/Folder 1: 37
    - Renik, Vladimir, 1929-1940
      Box/Folder 2: 1
    - Riephoff, J., 1933
      Box/Folder 2: 2
    - Shatilova (Grabbe), Anastasiia, 1985
      Box/Folder 2: 3
    - Shenshin, Petr, 1965
      Box/Folder 2: 4
    - Sole, Kent M., 1984-1985
      Box/Folder 2: 5
    - Solodkov, Nikolai Petrovich, 1933
      Box/Folder 2: 6
    - Spiro, Mariia, 1964
      Box/Folder 2: 7
    - Stakhevich, Mikhail Sergeevich, 1939
      Box/Folder 2: 8
    - Statsevich, Alex, 1964-1980
      Box/Folder 2: 9
    - Steblin-Kamenskii, I., 1937-1939
      Box/Folder 2: 10
    - Suzannet, Tatiana de, 1933
      Box/Folder 2: 11
    - Taisiia, Nun, 1980
      Box/Folder 2: 12
    - Tamara, Abbess, (Princess Tat'iana Konstantinovna (Constantinovna) of Russia), 1964-1977
      Box/Folder 2: 13
    - Teimuraz (Teymuraz) Konstantinovich (Constantinovich) Bagration-Mukhranskii, Prince of Russia, 1950-1989
      Box/Folder 2: 14
    - Tereshchenko, Sergei, 1930-1935
      Box/Folder 2: 15-16
    - Tsurikov, N., 1944
      Box/Folder 2: 17
    - Tzantzos, George (VITT Media International, Inc.), 1984 (Reel 3)
      Box/Folder 2: 18-19
      Includes book chapters.
    - Vasilii Aleksandrovich, Prince of Russia, 1963
      Box/Folder 2: 20
  - Subject file, 1903-1994
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Church and religion, 1963-1994
      Box/Folder 2: 21
      Includes printed matter and articles by various authors.
    - Costume Ball at Winter Palace illustrations, 1903
      Box/Folder 2: 22
    - Elizaveta Mavrikievna, Grand Duchess of Russia, testament and correspondence, 1922-1924
      Box/Folder 2: 23
    - Gavriil (Gabriel) Konstantinovich (Constantinovich), Prince of Russia, correspondence and clippings, 1938-1978
      Box/Folder 2: 24
    - Georgii (Georgy) Konstantinovich (Constantinovich), Prince of Russia, correspondence and speeches, 1922-1956
      Box/Folder 2: 25-26
    - Konstantin (Constantin) Konstantinovich (Constantinovich), Grand Duke of Russia, 1914-1985
      Box/Folder 3: 1-4
      Includes correspondence, photographs, memoirs by Princess Vera Konstantinovna (Constantinovna), and clippings.
    - The Romanov Family Association, correspondence and proposal statements, 1964-1984 (Reels 3-4)
      Box/Folder 3: 5-6 (Folder 5 is on Reel 3 and Folder 6 is on Reel 4)
    - Russo-Japanese War, campaign of 1905, correspondence and report, 1934-1938 (Reel 4)
      Box/Folder 3: 7
      Includes "Spas na vodakh'" manuscript by Petr Shabel'skii-Bork.
    - Soiuz revnitelei sviashchennoi pamiati Imperatora Nikolaia II, Paris, proclamation and activities report, 1922-1954
      Box/Folder 3: 8
  - Writings, 1927-1960
    - Memoir fragments, circa 1960
      Box/Folder 3: 9
    - Notes and drafts, 1927
      Box/Folder 3: 10
  - Writings by others, 1887-1977
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    - General, 1887-1977
      Box/Folder 3: 11-12
    - Alieva, Ekaterina, "Vstrechi s" Chlenami Tsarskoi Sem'i," memoir and poems, manuscripts, 1953-1959
      Box/Folder 3: 13
    - Bobrinskii, A., "Svetloi pamiati Kniazia Olega,", undated
      Box/Folder 3: 14
    - Nosovich, A. L., "Zapiski Vakhmistra Nosovicha,", 1967
      Box/Folder 3: 15
    - Tal'berg, N., Imperator Nikolai I v svete istoricheskoi pravdy (1853-1854), undated
      Box/Folder 3: 16
    - Voeikoff, Nicolas N., "The Russian Orthodox Monarchy,", circa 1970
      Box/Folder 3: 17
- Princess Tat'iana Konstantinovna (Constantinovna) of Russia papers from red trunks nos. 1-2, 1899-1945
  - Personal file, 1922-1929
    - Aleksandr (Alexander) Korochentsoff (Korotchenzoff) estate and death papers, 1922 (Reel 5)
      Box/Folder 4: 1
    - Inventory of possessions of Princess Tat'iana Konstantinovna (Constantinovna), 1923-1929
      Box/Folder 4: 2
  - Correspondence, 1899-1945
    - General, 1922-1944
      Box/Folder 4: 3-17
    - Invitations, 1922-1944
      Box/Folder 4: 18-20
    - Adamovich, Boris, 1929-1934
      Box/Folder 4: 21
    - Alborh, Lily, 1933
      Box/Folder 4: 22
    - Aleksandr Mikhailovich, Grand Duke of Russia, circa 1928
      Box/Folder 4: 23
    - Aleksei (Alexis) Bagration, Prince, 1933-1939
      Box/Folder 4: 24
    - Alexander I of Yugoslavia, 1928-1932
      Box/Folder 4: 25
    - Aliatov, Z., 1928-1930
      Box/Folder 4: 26
    - Altukhovich, V. P., 1929
      Box/Folder 4: 27
    - Amsler, R., 1928
      Box/Folder 4: 28
    - Anastasiia, Grand Duchess of Russia, 1932
      Box/Folder 4: 29
    - Anastasii, Metropolitan, 1940
      Box/Folder 4: 30
    - Antonii, Metropolitan, 1928-1932
      Box/Folder 4: 31
    - Aranovskaia, E., circa 1930
      Box/Folder 4: 32
    - Argamakova, Maria, 1926
      Box/Folder 4: 33
    - Ariadna, Ihumenia, 1939-1940
      Box/Folder 4: 34
    - Aristov, M., 1929
      Box/Folder 4: 35
    - Asperlin, Gaston le Rothien, 1937-1942
      Box/Folder 4: 36
    - "Ata" (Emma Karlovna Shadovets), nanny, 1922-1939
      Box/Folder 4: 37-41
    - Au Grand Passage, 1925 (Reel 6)
      Box/Folder 4: 42
    - Awajew, Piarrer, 1925
      Box/Folder 4: 43
    - Bacheracht, A. de, 1923-1926
      Box/Folder 4: 44
    - Bailly-Comte, N., 1932
      Box/Folder 4: 45
    - Baltazzi, Sophie, circa 1925
      Box/Folder 4: 46
    - Banun, Lulu, 1938-1943
      Box/Folder 4: 47
    - Bariatinskaia, Mariia, 1926
      Box/Folder 5: 1
    - Blanch, A. de, circa 1930
      Box/Folder 5: 2
    - Bogdanova, M., 1929
      Box/Folder 5: 3
    - Bonjour-Rachevski, Julie, 1923-1932
      Box/Folder 5: 4
    - Bossar, Eugenia, 1926-1940
      Box/Folder 5: 5-6
    - Botkin, P., 1925
      Box/Folder 5: 7
    - Bradley, Rebecca, 1929
      Box/Folder 5: 8
    - Brandt, Henriette, 1937-1938
      Box/Folder 5: 9
    - Brevern, Anatolii, 1926
      Box/Folder 5: 10
    - Briul', N., 1929-1930
      Box/Folder 5: 11
    - Bruel, E., 1931
      Box/Folder 5: 12
    - Buchen, J. von, circa 1925
      Box/Folder 5: 13
    - Butovich, Iulia, 1925-1938
      Box/Folder 5: 14
    - Burki, Lucie, 1922
      Box/Folder 5: 15
    - Cali, Ol'ga, 1933
      Box/Folder 5: 16
    - Chirikova, Olga, 1931
      Box/Folder 5: 17
    - Chubov, David, 1933
      Box/Folder 5: 18
    - Collet-Ramzeier, L., 1929-1940
      Box/Folder 5: 19
    - Coppier, Adele, 1933
      Box/Folder 5: 20
    - Cort, John L., 1940
      Box/Folder 5: 21
    - Deonna, Edmee, circa 1940
      Box/Folder 5: 22
    - Depreiss, Irina, 1937-1939
      Box/Folder 5: 23
    - Diakova, N. and M., 1925-1940
      Box/Folder 5: 24
    - Dositei (Dossithey), Bishop, 1927
      Box/Folder 5: 25
    - Donner, Nikolai N., 1933
      Box/Folder 5: 26
    - Dukhonina, Natalia, 1926-1939
      Box/Folder 5: 27-29
    - Dumond, L. M., 1926
      Box/Folder 5: 30
    - Dupasquier, 1928
      Box/Folder 5: 31
    - Egorova, Anna, 1927
      Box/Folder 5: 32
    - Ehaney, Marie, 1924-1940
      Box/Folder 5: 33
    - Elisabeth, Princess of Greece and Denmark, 1941
      Box/Folder 5: 34
    - Elizaveta Mavrikievna, Grand Duchess of Russia, 1924-1925
      Box/Folder 5: 35-36
    - Elles, Sophie, 1940
      Box/Folder 5: 37
    - Empeyta, Eugene, 1922
      Box/Folder 5: 38
    - Ensh, Edit, 1925
      Box/Folder 5: 39
    - Evgeniia, Igumenia, 1929 (Reel 7)
      Box/Folder 5: 40
    - Fabhebert, R., 1925
      Box/Folder 5: 41
    - Favre, Robert, 1931
      Box/Folder 5: 42
    - Fedorov, Mikhail, 1933
      Box/Folder 5: 43
    - Feganov (Feganoff), N., 1925
      Box/Folder 5: 44
    - Feodosii, Hieromonk, 1929-1930
      Box/Folder 5: 45
    - Fox, M., 1931
      Box/Folder 5: 46
    - Frolov, V., 1925
      Box/Folder 5: 47
    - Gaille, M., 1928
      Box/Folder 5: 48
    - Gavriil (Gabriel) Konstantinovich (Constantinovich), Prince of Russia, 1922-1943
      Box/Folder 5: 49-52, 6: 1-7
    - Gebzattel, S., 1923-1933
      Box/Folder 6: 8
    - Georgii (Georgy) Konstantinovich (Constantinovich), Prince of Russia, 1928
      Box/Folder 6: 9
    - Geyger, Putzy, 1939-1940
      Box/Folder 6: 10
    - Gilliard, Pierre, 1926-1928
      Box/Folder 6: 11
    - Glaser, Aleksandra Andreevna, 1925-1943
      Box/Folder 6: 12
    - Gloor, Aleksandra, 1932-1933
      Box/Folder 6: 13
    - Golitsyna, Anna, 1930
      Box/Folder 6: 14
    - Golovkov, Ivan, 1930
      Box/Folder 6: 15
    - Gonseth, Henri, 1927-1931
      Box/Folder 6: 16
    - Gorchakova, Ol'ga and Dardel, 1929-1940
      Box/Folder 6: 17
    - Goriachkovskii, 1927-1940
      Box/Folder 6: 18
    - Gretillat, Nelly, 1940
      Box/Folder 6: 19
    - Guillermin, Paul, 1928
      Box/Folder 6: 20
    - Gulevich, Arsenii, 1933
      Box/Folder 6: 21
    - Hagedorn-Kater, Lily, 1939-1942
      Box/Folder 6: 22
    - Helen, Princess of Serbia, 1931-1937
      Box/Folder 6: 23
    - Horneffer, S. Ch., 1929-1942
      Box/Folder 6: 24
    - Hugl, Harriette, 1940
      Box/Folder 6: 25
    - Iambovskaia, 1923-1926
      Box/Folder 6: 26
    - Iazykov, Nilkolai and Zoia, 1925-1931
      Box/Folder 6: 27
    - Ignat'ev, L., 1922-1926
      Box/Folder 6: 28
    - Ilovaiskaia, Evgeniia, 1925
      Box/Folder 6: 29
    - Il'ina, S., 1927
      Box/Folder 6: 30
    - Ioann, Hieromonk, 1929-1931 (Reel 8)
      Box/Folder 6: 31
    - Irinei, Bishop, 1926
      Box/Folder 6: 32
    - Kallash, M., 1923
      Box/Folder 6: 33
    - Kamarovskaia, Natalia, 1937
      Box/Folder 6: 34
    - Kamenskaia, L., 1926
      Box/Folder 6: 35
    - Kantakuzin, Konstantin and Ekaterina (Katia), 1922-1940
      Box/Folder 6: 36-37
    - Katerine (Catherine) Ioannovna, Princess of Russia, 1941
      Box/Folder 6: 38
    - Kaspari, M. N., 1932
      Box/Folder 6: 39
    - Kauffman, Reginald Wright, 1925-1932
      Box/Folder 6: 40
    - Kazakovskii, 1922
      Box/Folder 6: 41
    - Kefeli, M., 1937
      Box/Folder 6: 42
    - Keiander, Varvara, 1925-1929
      Box/Folder 6: 43
    - Kepping, B. M., 1931
      Box/Folder 6: 44
    - Kessman, Anais, 1932-1940
      Box/Folder 6: 45
    - Khartmann, S., 1922-1923
      Box/Folder 6: 46
    - Kolchev, Leonid, 1922-1928
      Box/Folder 6: 47
    - Komisarzhevskii (Komisarjevsky), Ernestina and Theodore, 1935-1941
      Box/Folder 6: 48
    - Komstagius, V., 1923
      Box/Folder 6: 49
    - Koniar, Aleksandra, 1925-1932
      Box/Folder 6: 50
    - Koninov, Iliumzhan, 1929-1930
      Box/Folder 6: 51
    - Konosovskii, A., 1940
      Box/Folder 7: 1
    - Konstantin (Constantin) Konstantinovich (Constantinovich), Prince of Russia and Tat'iana Konstantinovna (Constantinovna), Princess of Russia to their father Konstantin (Constantin) Konstantinovich (Constantinovich), Grand Duke of Russia, 1899
      Box/Folder 7: 2
    - Korf (Korff), S., 1927-1930
      Box/Folder 7: 3
    - Korob'in, G. and E., 1931-1940
      Box/Folder 7: 4
    - Korochentsov (Korochentzoff), Aleksei and Lilly, 1922-1940
      Box/Folder 7: 5-9
    - Kotsebu, Riurik, 1925
      Box/Folder 7: 10
    - Krieger, M., circa 1930 (Reel 9)
      Box/Folder 7: 11
    - Krupenskii, A., 1931
      Box/Folder 7: 12
    - Kruzenshtern, Ada Aleksandrovna, 1931
      Box/Folder 7: 13
    - Kuffland, V., 1926
      Box/Folder 7: 14
    - Kuris, L., circa 1928
      Box/Folder 7: 15
    - Kutaisova, E., 1923-1931
      Box/Folder 7: 16
    - Kvasnevskaia, M., 1940
      Box/Folder 7: 17
    - Laiming, Aleksandr and Ol'ga, 1922-1928
      Box/Folder 7: 18-19
    - Lambossy, E., circa 1925
      Box/Folder 7: 20
    - Lamm family, 1932-1940
      Box/Folder 7: 21
    - Lefort, R., 1940
      Box/Folder 7: 22
    - Leikhtenbergskaia, Mariia, 1931
      Box/Folder 7: 23
    - Levitskaia (Levitsky), Anna, 1925-1940
      Box/Folder 7: 24
    - Levitskii, K., 1939
      Box/Folder 7: 25
    - Liutsedarskaia, Zinaida, 1939
      Box/Folder 7: 26
    - Lodyzhenskii family, 1925-1940
      Box/Folder 7: 27
    - Lusanna, Zakonnica, 1923
      Box/Folder 7: 28
    - Makharoblidze, E., 1928-1930
      Box/Folder 7: 29
    - Mannerheim, Sof'ia Gustavovna, 1940
      Box/Folder 7: 30
    - Maria Feodorovna, Dowager Empress of Russia, 1921-1927
      Box/Folder 7: 31
    - Marina Petrovna, Princess of Russia, 1933-1942
      Box/Folder 7: 32
    - Marthe, D., 1922
      Box/Folder 7: 33
    - Maslov, Petr, 1933-1937
      Box/Folder 7: 34
    - Matuskov, Ivan, 1926
      Box/Folder 7: 35
    - Mdivani, E., 1940
      Box/Folder 7: 36
    - Meiendorff, Alina, 1929-1930
      Box/Folder 7: 37
    - Meiendorff, Helene, 1923-1929
      Box/Folder 7: 38
    - Mel'nik, Tat'iana, 1921
      Box/Folder 7: 39
    - Mel'nikova (Mielnikowa) S., 1926
      Box/Folder 7: 40
    - Meuron, Isabella de, 1940-1945
      Box/Folder 7: 41
    - Miaurin, Marcelle, circa 1925
      Box/Folder 7: 42
    - Milich, Elena, 1922-1928
      Box/Folder 7: 43
    - Militsa (Militza) Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess of Russia, 1929
      Box/Folder 7: 44
    - Miller, Evgenii, 1928
      Box/Folder 7: 45
    - Miller, Zoia and Mara, 1926-1931
      Box/Folder 7: 46
    - Mordvinova, Ol'ga, 1925
      Box/Folder 7: 47
    - Murav'eva-Apostol, N., 1929-1944
      Box/Folder 7: 48
    - Narmont, Valentina Fedorovna, 1925-1930
      Box/Folder 7: 49
    - Naryshkina, Natal'ia, 1925
      Box/Folder 7: 50
    - Natal'ia Konstantinovna (Constantinovna) Bagration-Mukhranskaia-Johnston, Princess, 1922-1945 (Reels 9-10)
      Box/Folder 8: 1-9 (Folders 1-3 on Reel 9, Folders 4-9 on Reel 10)
    - Naville, Édouard, 1940 (Reel 10)
      Box/Folder 8: 10
    - Nef, Ol'ga, 1925-1940
      Box/Folder 8: 11
    - Nesterovskaia, Antonina Rafailovna, 1922-1940
      Box/Folder 8: 12-16
    - Nezym, Semen Semenovich, 1931-1932
      Box/Folder 8: 17
    - Nicolopus, Tasso, 1922-1940 (Reels 10-11)
      Box/Folder 8: 18-20 (Folders 18-19 on Reel 10, Folder 20 on Reel 11)
    - Nikita Aleksandrovich, Prince of Russia, 1929-1942 (Reel 11)
      Box/Folder 8: 21
    - Nikol'skii, Boris, 1931-1933
      Box/Folder 8: 22
    - Nina Bagration-Mukhranskaia, Princess, 1919-1933
      Box/Folder 8: 23-25
    - Offenberg, Liudmila, 1940
      Box/Folder 8: 26
    - Ol'ga Aleksandrovna, Grand Duchess of Russia, 1924
      Box/Folder 8: 27
    - Ol'ga Konstantinovna (Constantinovna), Grand Duchess of Russia, 1922-1927
      Box/Folder 8: 28
    - Olsuf'eva (Olsoufieff), Tatiana, 1923-1943
      Box/Folder 8: 29-31
    - Orlov (Orloff), Sergei (Serge), 1923-1937
      Box/Folder 9: 1-3
    - Orlov-Davydov (Orloff-Davidoff), Thecla Staal, 1926-1933
      Box/Folder 9: 4
    - Orlova, E., 1922-1940
      Box/Folder 9: 5
    - Pakhomii, Hierodeacon, 1933
      Box/Folder 9: 6
    - Paleolog, Sergei, 1929
      Box/Folder 9: 7
    - Pashicheva, E., 1930-1936
      Box/Folder 9: 8
    - Pastukhov (Pastuhov), V., 1941
      Box/Folder 9: 9
    - Peter Nikolaevich, Grand Duke and Anastasiia, Grand Duchess, Princess of Montenegro, 1925
      Box/Folder 9: 10
    - Petrovich (Petrovitch), N., 1926-1931
      Box/Folder 9: 11
    - Planckner, Marie, 1927-1938
      Box/Folder 9: 12
    - Polezhaev, S., 1925
      Box/Folder 9: 13
    - Popov (Popoff), Aleksandr, 1937
      Box/Folder 9: 14
    - Popovitskii, A. and E., 1925-1930
      Box/Folder 9: 15
    - Poznanskaia, Natal'ia, 1925-1940
      Box/Folder 9: 16
    - Prokof'ev, M. and Ev., 1928-1931
      Box/Folder 9: 17
    - Proletov, E. and M., 1928-1940
      Box/Folder 9: 18-19
    - Prouille, J., 1932
      Box/Folder 9: 20
    - Putiatin, Mikhail and Sofia, 1925-1929 (Reel 12)
      Box/Folder 9: 21
    - Racine, Mg., 1924
      Box/Folder 9: 22
    - Ram, Mariia, 1935-1937
      Box/Folder 9: 23
    - Ram, Natalia, 1925-1941
      Box/Folder 9: 24
    - Rambalch, C. de, 1925-1928
      Box/Folder 9: 25
    - Rechenberg, Marie F., 1941
      Box/Folder 9: 26
    - Reibold de la Tour, Ellen, 1944
      Box/Folder 9: 27
    - Richardson, N., 1927-1930
      Box/Folder 9: 28
    - Rikhter, N., 1932
      Box/Folder 9: 29
    - Rimskii-Korsakov, Vladimir Valer'ianovich, 1928-1932
      Box/Folder 9: 30
    - Robert Marchand & Co., 1927-1931
      Box/Folder 9: 31
    - Roberti, E. de, 1925
      Box/Folder 9: 32
    - Rostovtseva, Mariia, 1924-1925
      Box/Folder 9: 33
    - Saburov, Petr and Elena, 1923-1930
      Box/Folder 9: 34
    - Saksonskii, Mark (Marc), 1937-1942
      Box/Folder 9: 35
    - Savva, Hieromonk, 1931
      Box/Folder 9: 36
    - Schleiffer, N., 1927
      Box/Folder 9: 37
    - Schulenburg, Margarita, 1922-1939
      Box/Folder 9: 38
    - Schulenburg, V., Count, 1922-1930
      Box/Folder 9: 39
    - Selezneva fon Vil'ke, M., 1937
      Box/Folder 9: 40
    - Serafim, Archbishop, 1929-1931
      Box/Folder 9: 41
    - Shakhovskaia, A. and S., 1927
      Box/Folder 9: 42
    - Shakhovskoi, Vladimir Aleksandrovich, 1922-1925
      Box/Folder 9: 43
    - Shapron, Natal'ia, 1923-1929
      Box/Folder 9: 44
    - Sheremetev, Sergei, 1925-1937
      Box/Folder 9: 45
    - Sheremeteva-Fabergé, Tatiana, 1926-1930
      Box/Folder 9: 46
    - Shidel'skii, V., 1929
      Box/Folder 9: 47
    - Skuratov, Konstantin, 1928-1933
      Box/Folder 9: 48
    - Smirnov (Smirnoff), Sergei (Serge), 1922-1940
      Box/Folder 9: 49-50
    - Sobolev, Nikolai, 1939-1940
      Box/Folder 10: 1
    - Sokolovskaia, Elena, 1933
      Box/Folder 10: 2
    - Solovikov (Solowikoff)-Rambach, K. N., 1922
      Box/Folder 10: 3
    - Souller, G., 1922-1924
      Box/Folder 10: 4
    - Spalaikovich, M., 1927
      Box/Folder 10: 5
    - Stefanovich, Andrei, 1929
      Box/Folder 10: 6
    - Stepanovich, N., 1927-1933
      Box/Folder 10: 7
    - Strandman, Julie, circa 1940
      Box/Folder 10: 8
    - Stromilova, A., 1928-1933
      Box/Folder 10: 9
    - Subbotin, Vladimir, 1928
      Box/Folder 10: 10
    - Suillerat, Cecile, 1939-1940
      Box/Folder 10: 11
    - Sviatopolk-Mirskaia, Sofiia, 1931-1942
      Box/Folder 10: 12
    - Sviderskaia, E., 1930 (Reel 13)
      Box/Folder 10: 13
    - Tatishchev, Nikolai, 1932
      Box/Folder 10: 14
    - The Tatler, 1926
      Box/Folder 10: 15
    - Teimuraz (Teymuraz) Konstantinovich (Constantinovich) Bagration-Mukhranskii, Prince, 1922-1951
      Box/Folder 10: 16-19
    - Tereshchenko family, 1925-1944
      Box/Folder 10: 20
    - Tieche, Edward, 1923-1924
      Box/Folder 10: 21
    - Trakhtenberg, Vasilii, 1923-1924
      Box/Folder 10: 22
    - Tschubov, D., 1937
      Box/Folder 10: 23
    - Tseis, S., 1938-1940
      Box/Folder 10: 24
    - Tsitovich, N., 1940
      Box/Folder 10: 25
    - Tumanova, Nina, 1939
      Box/Folder 10: 26
    - Tyrkova, Nadezhda, 1923
      Box/Folder 10: 27
    - Uvarova, Ekaterina, 1926
      Box/Folder 10: 28
    - Vakhrushev (Wakhroucheff), P., 1927
      Box/Folder 10: 29
    - Valkonen, Lidia Nikolaevna, 1923
      Box/Folder 10: 30
    - Vatatsi, A., 1923-1928
      Box/Folder 10: 31
    - Vera Konstantinovna (Constantinovna), Princess of Russia, 1923-1944
      Box/Folder 10: 32-34
      Includes letters from her nanny "Ata" (Emma Karlovna Shadovets).
    - Vesinand, E., 1925
      Box/Folder 10: 35
    - Vitkovskaia, Anna, 1923-1926
      Box/Folder 10: 36